<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer-vision on Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</title>
    <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/tags/computer-vision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer-vision on Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018  · Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://benedictflorance.github.io/tags/computer-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Deep Domain Adaption for Object Detection</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/domain-adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/domain-adaptation/</guid>
      <description>Recipient of the Mitacs Globalink Research Internship to work on &amp;ldquo;Unsupervised Deep Domain Adaptation for Object Detection&amp;rdquo; under the mentorship of Prof. Eric Granger at Le Laboratoire d’imagerie, de vision et d’intelligence artificielle (LIVIA), ETS Montreal, Canada. Working on an unsupervised, still-image to videos domain adaptation by leveraging the temporal coherence of the videos from the target domain with the help of a tracker
 Analyzed the distribution gap and performed studies on local features to show the vulnerabilities of the existing image-to-image adaptation approaches that under-perform on face-detection datasets like SCUT-A, SCUT-B and Widerface but show remarkable results on datasets like Cityscape and SIM10k</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights Generation and Player Analysis for Broadcast Cricket Videos</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/cricket/</guid>
      <description> Employed video frame segmentation and replay detection on a newly constructed dataset of IPL cricket videos. Working on a video classification network for events like boundaries, sixes, wickets and milestones
 Conducted a study on the real-world implementation of sports analytics by interviewing Mr. K.S. Viswanathan, CEO of Chennai Super Kings, the most successful franchise cricket team and other experts from the domain
 Dataset Link: Click Here
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Flora Project</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/indianflora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 01:27:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/indianflora/</guid>
      <description>Awarded the prestigious Indian Academy of Sciences’ Summer Research Fellowship (SRFP) to work on &amp;ldquo;Indian Flora Project&amp;rdquo;, a plant species identification and disease detection system under the supervision of Prof. Dr. C. V. Jawahar at Centre for Visual Information Technology (CVIT), IIIT - Hyderabad. Performed transfer learning on various CNN models using our new Indic-Leaf dataset of 112 Indian plants for identification and disease detection with results showing Top-1 and Top-5 precision of 90.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>