<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internship on Benedict Florance</title>
    <link>http://benedictflorance.me/tags/internship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internship on Benedict Florance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018  · Benedict Florance</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 01:27:06 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://benedictflorance.me/tags/internship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Flora Project</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.me/project/indianflora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 01:27:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.me/project/indianflora/</guid>
      <description>The full project report can be found here. Employed Convolutional Neural Network model (ResNet18) by iterating through several different models trained from-the-scratch, fine-tuned on ImageNet, PlantCLEF Encyclopedia of Life, PlantCLEF noisy web datasets on a manually collected, robust dataset of 100 Indian plant species. (using PyTorch) Experimental observations show efficient computation time and high top-5 precision of 99.85% compared to the low performance of state-of-the-art approaches that focus on hand-engineered features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Railways EMU Production Application</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.me/project/icf-chennai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 01:04:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.me/project/icf-chennai/</guid>
      <description>The application can be found here. Developed the backend service for digitizing the records of inventory management, production planning and status updates of the coaches and rakes under the Digital India initiative. Wrote API’s in Laravel framework to handle authorization across Web and Android clients. The code was reviewed and pushed to production. The Android application has been released on Google Play Store and is used by more than 500 employees of ICF, Chennai for internal purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>