<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internship on Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</title>
    <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/tags/internship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internship on Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018  · Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://benedictflorance.github.io/tags/internship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Deep Domain Adaption for Object Detection</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/domain-adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/domain-adaptation/</guid>
      <description>Recipient of the Mitacs Globalink Research Internship to work on &amp;ldquo;Unsupervised Deep Domain Adaptation for Object Detection&amp;rdquo; under the mentorship of Prof. Eric Granger at Le Laboratoire d’imagerie, de vision et d’intelligence artificielle (LIVIA), ETS Montreal, Canada
 Analyzed how local features, distribution gap metrics and usage of trackers to obtain temporal coherence of target domain videos can be leveraged to eliminate the vulnerabilities of the existing unsupervised adaptation approaches that under-perform on face-detection datasets like SCUT and Widerface</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights Generation for Broadcast Cricket Videos</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/cricket/</guid>
      <description> Employed video frame segmentation, replay and scoreboard detection on a newly constructed dataset of IPL cricket videos.
 Conducted a study on the real-world implementation of sports analytics by interviewing Mr. K.S. Viswanathan, CEO of Chennai Super Kings, the most successful franchise cricket team and other experts from the domain
 Dataset Link: Click Here
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Flora Project</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/indianflora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 01:27:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/indianflora/</guid>
      <description>Awarded the prestigious Indian Academy of Sciences’ Summer Research Fellowship (SRFP) to work on &amp;ldquo;Indian Flora Project&amp;rdquo;, a plant species identification and disease detection system under the supervision of Prof. Dr. C. V. Jawahar at Centre for Visual Information Technology (CVIT), IIIT - Hyderabad.
 Performed transfer learning on various CNN models using our new Indic-Leaf dataset of 112 Indian plants for identification and disease detection with results showing Top-1 and Top-5 precision of 90.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Railways EMU Production Application</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/icf-chennai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 01:04:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/icf-chennai/</guid>
      <description>Developed the backend service for digitizing the records of inventory management, production planning and status updates of the coaches and rakes under the Digital India initiative
 Wrote API’s in Laravel framework to handle authorization across Web and Android clients
 The code was reviewed and pushed to production.
 The Android application has been released on Google Play Store and is used by more than 500 employees of ICF, Chennai for internal purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>