<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android-app on Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</title>
    <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/tags/android-app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android-app on Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020  · Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 01:04:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://benedictflorance.github.io/tags/android-app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Railways EMU Production Application</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/icf-chennai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 01:04:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/icf-chennai/</guid>
      <description>Developed the backend service for digitizing the records of inventory management, production planning and status updates of the coaches and rakes under the Digital India initiative
 Wrote API’s in Laravel framework to handle authorization across Web and Android clients
 The code was reviewed and pushed to production.
 The Android application has been released on Google Play Store and is used by more than 500 employees of ICF, Chennai for internal purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Healthcare System</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/smart-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/smart-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>Implemented deep learning models to predict disease risks based on user symptoms and lifestyle inputs as a collaborative pipeline between doctors and patients. Used web-scraped data for training the model
 Built a recommendation system for analyzing the abnormal parameters and recommending future course of action like medicines and wrote APIs in Laravel for the Android application where the features were deployed
 This project received a Special Mention at the Pragyan Hackathon conducted at SAP Labs, Bangalore.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>