<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine-learning on Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</title>
    <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine-learning on Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018  · Benedict Florance Arockiaraj</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://benedictflorance.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensemble-based Endoscopy Artefact Detection</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/endoscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/endoscopy/</guid>
      <description>Proposed an ensemble of RetinaNet-based object detectors to localize bounding boxes and predict labels of eight different artefact classes that generalizes to an inter-patient, multi-tissue and a multi-modal corpus ofendoscopy video frame data.
 The common artefacts of interest that corrupt endoscopy video frames include contrast, saturation, instrument, blood, specularity, blur, imaging artefacts and bubbles.
 Achieved an mAP of 0.3405 improving existing state-of-the-art results.
 Thesis Link: Click Here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised 3D Human Pose Estimation</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/humanpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/humanpose/</guid>
      <description> Working on a kinematic-structure-preserved unsupervised 3D pose estimation framework that uses differen-tiable transformations to effectively disentangle pose, foreground and background appearance information on Human3.6M, MPI-INF-3DHP, LSP, Youtube and 3DPW datasets  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Deep Domain Adaption for Object Detection</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/domain-adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/domain-adaptation/</guid>
      <description>Recipient of the Mitacs Globalink Research Internship to work on &amp;ldquo;Unsupervised Deep Domain Adaptation for Object Detection&amp;rdquo; under the mentorship of Prof. Eric Granger at Le Laboratoire d’imagerie, de vision et d’intelligence artificielle (LIVIA), ETS Montreal, Canada.
 Analyzed how local features, distribution gap metrics and usage of trackers to obtain temporal coherence of target domain videos can be leveraged to eliminate the vulnerabilities of the existing unsupervised adaptation approaches that under-perform on face-detection datasets like SCUT and Widerface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights Generation for Broadcast Cricket Videos</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/cricket/</guid>
      <description> Employed video frame segmentation, replay and scoreboarddetection on a newly constructed dataset of IPL cricket videos.
 Conducted a study on the real-world implementation of sports analytics by interviewing Mr. K.S. Viswanathan, CEO of Chennai Super Kings, the most successful franchise cricket team and other experts from the domain
 Dataset Link: Click Here
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Flora Project</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/indianflora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 01:27:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/indianflora/</guid>
      <description>Awarded the prestigious Indian Academy of Sciences’ Summer Research Fellowship (SRFP) to work on &amp;ldquo;Indian Flora Project&amp;rdquo;, a plant species identification and disease detection system under the supervision of Prof. Dr. C. V. Jawahar at Centre for Visual Information Technology (CVIT), IIIT - Hyderabad.
 Performed transfer learning on various CNN models using our new Indic-Leaf dataset of 112 Indian plants for identification and disease detection with results showing Top-1 and Top-5 precision of 90.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Healthcare System</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/smart-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/project/smart-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>* Implemented deep learning models to predict disease risks based on user symptoms and lifestyle inputs as a collaborative pipeline between doctors and patients. Used web-scraped data for training the model.
 Built a recommendation system for analyzing the abnormal parameters and recommending future course of action like medicines and wrote APIs in Laravel for the Android application where the features were deployed.
 This project received a Special Mention at the Pragyan Hackathon conducted at SAP Labs, Bangalore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking down Neural Networks: An intuitive approach to backprop!</title>
      <link>http://benedictflorance.github.io/post/backpropagation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 23:22:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://benedictflorance.github.io/post/backpropagation/</guid>
      <description>Whether you’re a beginner in machine learning or an expert, you would have had a hard time understanding the concept of backpropagation in neural networks. If you’re a beginner, the first look of the complex steps strung together in the backprop algorithm would’ve been definitely daunting. While a few of us would have spent time in analysing the algorithm and getting the intuition, most of us would have abstracted the learning process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>